A Guide to the Papers of Collins Denny, 1891-1974, and n. d.
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
Papers of Collins Denny 1891-1974 and n. d.
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
2672-p, -q, -r
This collection consists of 32 items.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
There are no restrictions.
Scope and Content Information
The collection contains Denny and Chapman oral history tales, and an autobiography by Elizabeth Chapman (Denny) Vann. There are also photographs, ambrotypes and a tintype of family members.
Contents List
- Postcard: Bishops of the Methodist Episcopal Church, South, including Collins Denny n. d.
- Tintype of John Henry Denny, Collins Denny's brother. n. d.
- 2 Photographs of Mary Brown (Denny) Campbell. 1881 and n. d.
- Photograph of the Denny House at Vanderbilt University, includes historical notes. ca. 1891?
- 2 Photographs of Col. William R. Denny, includes biographical notes. 1897 and n. d.
- 2 Photographs of Elizabeth Chapman Denny Vann. 1904 and 1953
- "Autobiographical Sketch of Elizabeth Chapman Denny Vann. 1972-1973, TMs (photocopy). 13 pp.
- "Denny and Chapman Oral History Tales," by Elizabeth C. Denny Vann. 1973, TMs (carbon). 25 pp.
- Congressional Record, House of Representatives, includes a letter: Elizabeth C. Denny Vann to Nancy Hawkins re: politics 50 years ago 1974 July 29
- Photograph of Joseph Scrogin Collins, maternal grandfather of Bishop Collins Denny. n. d.
- 2 Photographs, Bishop Collins Denny and Mrs. Collins Denny, includes biographical notes. n. d.
- Photograph of Robert Wiseman Huffman and Sarah Noland Huffman, including genealogical notes. n. d.
- Genealogical notes (photocopy) re: Kate Baker, daughter of William and Margaret Denny, and of William Joseph Denny. n. d.
- Photograph of "Angerona," home of Col. William R. Denny, Winchester, Virginia. n. d.
- Photograph of the Rev. Sir Henry Lyttleton Lister Denny, genealogist, includes biographical notes. n. d.
- Photograph of William Denny of Newtown, Virginia, paternal grandfather of Collins Denny, includes genealogical notes. n. d.
- Photograph of Joseph Seigel Denny, son of Robert Lewis Denny, includes genealogical note. n. d.
- 2 Photographs, Daniel Chase and Lucy Staples Chase, his wife, includes genealogical notes. n. d.
- Photograph of an ambrotype of Collins Denny, Kate Baker Denny, and Mary Brown Denny (Mrs. Harvey J. Campbell). n. d.
- Photograph of an ambrotype: of Lucy Chase Chapman. n. d.
- Ambrotype: Collins Denny, Kate Baker Denny, and Mary Brown Denny (Mrs. Harvey J. Campbell). n. d.
- Ambrotype: Lucy Chase Chapman. n. d.
- Ambrotype: Collins Denny. n. d.
- Photograph of [Mr. and Mrs. White?], (Edith D. White). n. d.
- Photograph of Edith D. White. n. d.
- Photograph of [Mrs. White's parents?]. n. d.
- Photograph of two children, unidentified. n. d.
- Photograph of Edith Denny White. n. d.
- Photograph of Roscoe Marvin White (1881-1973), as a child. n. d.
- 2 Photographs of the Parsonage, Charlottesville, Virginia, birthplace of Edith Denny White. n. d.
- Photograph of the gravestone of Margaret A. Denny. n. d.
- Photograph (photocopy) of the birthplace of Collins Denny, Winchester, Virginia.